the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet with
xenophilography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of Holo talk
for the week of October 4th 1999. it's
getting pretty close to the time where I
have to upload this to the web in fact
it's eight o'clock on Sunday night I'd
like to have this up at least 9 or 10
o'clock so we're going to be doing this
live tonight Our Guest this week is Ray
Ramirez and he's going to be with us in
just a minute in fact I'm going to be
dialing his number live here from the
studio and getting him on uh before we
do I just want to
give you a few reminders the first
reminder is this Wednesday October 4th
1999 and I put that date in there just
in case someone's listening to this two
years and you know two years in the
future in the archives and they're
thinking that it's uh this week uh in
2002 no this is 1999 October 4th this
Wednesday open house the first one this
season here at the studio the Topic's
going to be
laser transmission Holograms we're gonna
have a little talk about laser
transmission Holograms and then go into
the lab and see
some of the laser transmission Holograms
these are really interesting Holograms
because normally people do not have an
opportunity to see these outside of a
laboratory environment because they
normally or usually all the time require
lasers in order to illuminate them and
therefore usually when you go to a
gallery or you're in a holography shop
you see holograms on the walls or
holograms on pedestals being illuminated
with white light sources but on occasion
you'll see a laser transmission hologram
sometimes in a more scientific exhibit
this will give you an opportunity to see
quite a few of these and it's going to
be a pretty interesting night so that's
this Wednesday evening October
what is that right October 6th I'm sorry
here I am giving you the wrong
information this Wednesday October 6th
at 7 30 p.m here at the studio in
Allentown
send me an email if you'd like more
information or you can call the Studio's
number at area code
610-7700341 that's
610-770-0341 lots of upcoming guests
coming on I'm not going to say who they
are because sometimes we have to switch
schedules around and things of that
nature so uh we'll just play it by ear
and if you get on the whole talk email
list you'll be able to find out which
guest is coming on for which week John
Clare who has been guest on the show and
was one of the very early players with
the uh laser pointer
holography
has made a nice diode hologram using
fiber optics and I'm going to get more
information from John this is very
exciting especially for school projects
so
um
another aspect to laser pointer diode
holography that you can that we can put
on in the books he says it's a nice
hologram and uh using fiber optics and
we're going to get more information from
John in the near future
if you have not upgraded your real audio
player excuse me to the new G2 player
and it's a free upgrade
um I would suggest that if you're going
to do that please do that this week I
have a brand new type of presentation
we're going to be adding to holotalk
which is the synchronized multimedia
integrated language or smile which
allows the combination of audio video
graphics pictures animation all through
the G2 player you do not need any
special Hardware you do not need any
special software you just need to
upgrade your regular real audio player
to the new RealPlayer G2 and that's a
free upgrade at the real site so you can
go there and download that and take
advantage of some of these new programs
that I'm going to be putting together
for whole talk that you would not be
able to take advantage of if you just
have the regular Real Player because it
does not support the smile language okay
getting about that time I'm seeing 757
on on the clock here I told Ray I'd give
him a call at five at five o'clock his
time out in California which is eight
o'clock our time here so I'm going to
put this on pose Chief well I wish I
could edit this I'm going to put this on
pause
to give Ray a call and get him online so
we'll be right back
hello is right there
sorry to keep everything oh Ray Hi how
are you pretty good I'd like to welcome
Ray Ramirez to hollow talk it's nice to
finally be able to get you on the show
after all the great work that you
could keep the lasers and Holograms with
your science fair projects before we get
started I was wondering if you could
tell the listeners a little bit about
yourself
what your age is what grade you are what
school you're in okay uh I'm 13 years
old I'm in the eighth grade and I go to
Terrace Hills Middle School in Grand
Terrace California and I understand you
started out last year working
um
with lasers and holography as a science
fair project yeah
how did you get started with something
like that were you interested in science
at the time oh no I really didn't like
science it was it was really boring I
was looking for a science fair project
and we had two weeks to do this project
that day I found the house made in a
book
my grandma
it hasn't been that easy but I decided
to do it and I asked my teacher and he
said that sounds like a pretty good
project
you kind of open up doors to electronics
and all the stuff I really didn't like
so before you got started you didn't
really like science and then after you
worked with it for a while you found out
that it was pretty cool yeah
you were one of the first people to
order my shoebox holography system back
when it was just a couple Xerox sheets
of eight and a half by eleven paper
before it was into the book
you find that helped you out a little
bit oh yeah it did just
knowing that it's not that hard you
don't need a big expensive if you need
to make Holograms
they helped me out a lot
a year the California state science fair
winner right yeah what does that feel
like I mean science fairs are so
competitive I mean it's you play
baseball
competitive baseball is
I mean winning the California state
science fairs like the World Series
right yeah I remember sitting at home
and I went to the California State
Center
website I was just reading how all these
people have done pretty good projects
and uh when the listing came out of
everyone's project I sat there and
circled the ones that
problem
and uh and I remember I was looking at
the website a few months before the
state time for him hoping there might
have a chance
so you got a plan of action yeah and you
went and you actually took a number of
science fairs getting there right uh
yeah there were three before the state
times or so four total wow that must be
an incredible feeling
that's fair
I should have tried holography back when
I was in school of course I would have
paid like ten thousand dollars for a
heenie back then do you think that the
uh the reason that you found this
fantasy was the fact that
that the cost was so low as well
well you know really when I first
started I didn't know anything about the
diet I really I didn't know you when I
first started up and
and I was going to the PCC and viewing
my hologram there I made a few more
games there and I wanted to do it on my
own and Maya yeah
yeah you found out what was involved
what problems did you find with it
they had to be overcome having someone
like Fred there just he knew what he was
doing but when I was doing it by myself
it's
um it's pretty hard to get a room
totally dark
and just buying things keeper have its
Advantage but there's a reason why
they're cheaper sometimes they're not as
good because like that like to save ones
aren't all the way green
there were other kids that were
listening to this that were thinking
about doing
lasers and pornography for a science
fair project do you have any tips or
suggestions that you would give to them
um one of the big things that that
people tell me I've done is
I think I've done a little bit and be
very motivated
it doesn't really matter how you get
your motivation it'd be very nice to be
self-loaded to want to do it yourself
but you have to look for some reason why
you want to do this
like for example if you don't like
playing the piano you're not going to be
a very good man but you don't press you
don't want to do it so you have the one
you're the one what's your motivation I
I just I don't know it's
is that a wealth that all of us
holographers have
kind of the final the final product what
it actually looks like when it's done
not too much from anywhere else like it
was kind of I could do it if I wanted to
see if it wasn't there was no pressure
what
um what are some of your future plans
for holography do you plan on continuing
with it
um yeah I wanna I'm building a bigger
Lab at my grandparents house right now
and um kind of causing stuff when I see
it and hopefully I want to build a post
Blazer and maybe a yag I want to do some
post ways of holography
stereo guns and things like that and he
told you told me you may be getting one
of the uh green pointers in yeah they
plan working with those as well yeah the
company has really close to you give me
a green laser pointer and um hopefully
gonna do some experiments with that and
hopefully get some walking make a few
hours you have plans for a website in
the future yeah I want to start a
website I'm working on it a little bit
and um I just want to have some
experiments that I've done and things
like that on there
oh that would be good for people to look
up information on the experiments
themselves
then you have to start answering all the
email
what do you think about that I it's fun
I like to help people with it's when
seeing people start off when I started
off and they're having some of the same
problems that I had or still having it's
kind of fun are you are you interested
in art are you going to pursue
holographies and artistic means of
expression
um no I I know a few people who like the
art part of it but I really like the
science part of it like why it worked
um the other part of it is I don't
understand all the art part of it
[Music]
yeah yeah well it definitely takes a
person who has the abilities in both the
creative thought process and also the
scientific thought process as well to ex
to excel as
yeah I think it'd be great to have an
artist start making all of them
there's a lot they can do would you like
to exhibit your work someday uh yeah
that'd be that'd be really fun
people looking at my hologram why don't
you send me one of your Holograms and
I'll put it up okay I'll put it up over
at the Discovery Center it's a new
science museum over by High University
right now I'm I'm within the next few
weeks I've been trying to do a
shadowgram with a little laser pointer
and uh
come on that looks pretty good I'm gonna
shoot it I'm not sure if it's going to
be on lavish film or Agra yeah
that was the materials that you've
worked with well I started off when I
first started off I had a box of feed
like the fourth Apple pack and I blew
all of those I got almost
one of them but uh the other three I
blew and I've used some ankles and
um some Russian Russian Film
and you find all of them the people it's
really easy to work with I hate the um
the psg03m and it's really hard to work
with but yeah at low powers like that
right yeah I was doing 30 second
exposures and I actually got a little
bit but not in the not in the 03m
the weird process
but I like the pfgl1
now when you work with that you expose
that film to any white light no late
classification no I think you do I have
been but I think you do it with the o3m
but uh three yeah I I haven't done it
with the 01. any comments you want to
make to anyone before we close the show
out
I'm just listening to people run up and
down the steps I don't know what's going
on upstairs I do the stand in the studio
and everybody's running up and down the
steps I don't know what the heck's going
on so that's why there was a little bit
of a blank space there for a minute wow
yeah okay I'm gonna go eat dinner right
now you better go eat dinner yeah that's
right it's like 5 47 out there right
yeah yeah well I'm gonna have this show
up probably within the next hour so uh
when you log on maybe you'll be able to
get on and see it okay or listen to it
rather not see it do you have real
player G2
um or just a real player Real Player
Okay because I'm going to be doing some
pretty neat stuff at the G2 system is
that a free download yeah it's a free
it's actually a upgrade just from the
5.0 okay and it's free
it combines a lot of different
multimedia things and graphics and texts
and things into one
I'm going to start doing that with the
g2 yeah you have to start your own radio
show so I can log on and listen to you
I'm the only pornography I can't log on
and enjoy a show every week
I'd like to be able to just sit back you
know with a cup of tea and listen to
somebody do a show yeah
so why don't you send me one of your
Holograms okay and I'll get it up and
displayed put information up about you
as well because I know you sent an
information packet as well and I'll make
sure that information gets up there with
it and then get some people to uh
your hologram maybe gets an email from
them get some fan mail and
congratulations on all your achievements
thank you and you're pretty certain
you're going to stick with holography
huh yeah so someone wants you keep an
eye on
the last few years Ray Ramirez from
California what city Riverside Riverside
California staff side of Los Angeles
[Music]
oh okay North Los Angeles north or south
of you
um Southwest
okay so you're you're up further north
you're up on the way towards uh San
Francisco no Denver yeah okay I don't
know too much about California okay
they're closer to San Diego
all right well thanks for being on the
show all right and I want to wish you a
lot of luck and a lot of success and I'm
looking forward to following your future
Pursuits and
the field of Photography I'll see you
later okay bye